{"test_questions": [[{"question": "Convert hexadecimal value 16 to decimal.", "opta": "2210", "optb": "1610", "optc": "1010", "optd": "2010", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to 8-bit binary.187", "opta": "101110112", "optb": "110111012", "optc": "101111012", "optd": "101111002", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert binary 111111110010 to hexadecimal.", "opta": "EE216", "optb": "FF216", "optc": "2FE16", "optd": "FD216", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following binary number to decimal. 010112", "opta": "11", "optb": "35", "optc": "15", "optd": "10", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the binary number 1001.00102 to decimal.", "opta": "90.125", "optb": "9.125", "optc": "125", "optd": "12.5", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Decode the following ASCII message. 1010011101010010101011000100101100101000001001000100000110100101000100", "opta": "STUDYHARD", "optb": "STUDY HARD", "optc": "stydyhard", "optd": "study hard", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The voltages in digital electronics are continuously variable.", "opta": "True", "optb": "False", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "One hex digit is sometimes referred to as a(n):", "opta": "byte", "optb": "nibble", "optc": "grouping", "optd": "instruction", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the most widely used alphanumeric code for computer input and output?", "opta": "Gray", "optb": "ASCII", "optc": "Parity", "optd": "EBCDIC", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "If a typical PC uses a 20-bit address code, how much memory can the CPU address?", "opta": "20 MB", "optb": "10 MB", "optc": "1 MB", "optd": "580 MB", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 59.7210 to BCD.", "opta": "111011", "optb": "01011001.01110010", "optc": "1110.11", "optd": "0101100101110010", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 8B3F16 to binary.", "opta": "35647", "optb": "011010", "optc": "1011001111100011", "optd": "1000101100111111", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is typically the longest: bit, byte, nibble, word?", "opta": "Bit", "optb": "Byte", "optc": "Nibble", "optd": "Word", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Assign the proper odd parity bit to the code 111001.", "opta": "1111011", "optb": "1111001", "optc": "0111111", "optd": "0011111", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert decimal 64 to binary.", "opta": "01010010", "optb": "01000000", "optc": "00110110", "optd": "01001000", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert hexadecimal value C1 to binary.", "opta": "11000001", "optb": "1000111", "optc": "111000100", "optd": "111000001", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following octal number to decimal. 178", "opta": "51", "optb": "82", "optc": "57", "optd": "15", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following binary number to octal. 0101111002", "opta": "1728", "optb": "2728", "optc": "1748", "optd": "2748", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many binary digits are required to count to 10010?", "opta": "7", "optb": "2", "optc": "3", "optd": "100", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The BCD number for decimal 347 is ________.", "opta": "1100 1011 1000", "optb": "0011 0100 0111", "optc": "0011 0100 0001", "optd": "1100 1011 0110", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary number for octal 458 is ________.", "opta": "100010", "optb": "100101", "optc": "110101", "optd": "100100", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sum of 11101 + 10111 equals ________.", "opta": "110011", "optb": "100001", "optc": "110100", "optd": "100100", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following binary number to decimal. 100110102", "opta": "154", "optb": "155", "optc": "153", "optd": "157", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The decimal number 188 is equal to the binary number ________.", "opta": "10111100", "optb": "0111000", "optc": "1100011", "optd": "1111000", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following binary number to octal. 0011010112", "opta": "1538", "optb": "3518", "optc": "2538", "optd": "3528", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many bits are in an ASCII character?", "opta": "16", "optb": "8", "optc": "7", "optd": "4", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A binary number's value changes most drastically when the ________ is changed.", "opta": "MSB", "optb": "frequency", "optc": "LSB", "optd": "duty cycle", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert decimal 213 to binary.", "opta": "11001101", "optb": "11010101", "optc": "01111001", "optd": "11100011", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The decimal number for octal 748 is ________.", "opta": "74", "optb": "60", "optc": "22", "optd": "62", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The sum of the two BCD numbers, 0011 + 0011, is ________.", "opta": "0110", "optb": "0111", "optc": "0011", "optd": "1100", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert binary 01001110 to decimal.", "opta": "4E", "optb": "78", "optc": "76", "optd": "116", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which is not a word size?", "opta": "64", "optb": "28", "optc": "16", "optd": "8", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The octal numbering system:", "opta": "simplifies tasks", "optb": "groups binary numbers in groups of 4", "optc": "saves time", "optd": "simplifies tasks and saves time", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary number 1110 is equal to the decimal number ________.", "opta": "3", "optb": "1", "optc": "7", "optd": "14", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following octal number to binary.768", "opta": "1101112", "optb": "1111102", "optc": "1111002", "optd": "1001112", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 11001010001101012 to hexadecimal.", "opta": "121035", "optb": "CA35", "optc": "53AC1", "optd": "530121", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to octal.281", "opta": "1348", "optb": "4318", "optc": "3318", "optd": "1338", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When using even parity, where is the parity bit placed?", "opta": "Before the MSB", "optb": "After the LSB", "optc": "In the parity word", "optd": "After the odd parity bit", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following octal number to decimal. 358", "opta": "71", "optb": "17", "optc": "92", "optd": "29", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert binary 11001111 to hexadecimal.", "opta": "8F16", "optb": "CE16", "optc": "DF16", "optd": "CF16", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 17318 to decimal.", "opta": "216.4", "optb": "985", "optc": "3D9", "optd": "1123", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An analog signal has a range from 0 V to 5 V. What is the total number of analog possibilities within this range?", "opta": "5", "optb": "50", "optc": "250", "optd": "infinite", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Hexadecimal letters A through F are used for decimal equivalent values from:", "opta": "1 through 6", "optb": "9 through 14", "optc": "10 through 15", "optd": "11 through 17", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to 8-bit binary.35", "opta": "000100102", "optb": "000100112", "optc": "001000112", "optd": "001000102", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following hexadecimal number to binary.C916", "opta": "101110012", "optb": "101110112", "optc": "100111002", "optd": "110010012", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to hexadecimal.125", "opta": "7D16", "optb": "D716", "optc": "7C16", "optd": "C716", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "A decimal 11 in BCD is ________.", "opta": "00001011", "optb": "00001100", "optc": "00010001", "optd": "00010010", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the resultant binary of the decimal problem 49 + 01 = ?", "opta": "01010101", "optb": "00110101", "optc": "00110010", "optd": "00110001", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The difference of 111 \u2013 001 equals ________.", "opta": "100", "optb": "111", "optc": "001", "optd": "110", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the binary number 1100 to Gray code.", "opta": "0011", "optb": "1010", "optc": "1100", "optd": "1001", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary number 11101011000111010 can be written in hexadecimal as ________.", "opta": "DD63A16", "optb": "1D63A16", "optc": "1D33A16", "optd": "1D63116", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is an invalid BCD code?", "opta": "0011", "optb": "1101", "optc": "0101", "optd": "1001", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What decimal number does 25 represent?", "opta": "10", "optb": "31", "optc": "25", "optd": "32", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the Gray code 1011 to binary.", "opta": "1011", "optb": "1010", "optc": "0100", "optd": "1101", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Determine the decimal equivalent of the signed binary number 11110100 in 1's complement.", "opta": "116", "optb": "\u201312", "optc": "11", "optd": "128", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the difference between binary coding and binary-coded decimal?", "opta": "BCD is pure binary.", "optb": "Binary coding has a decimal format.", "optc": "BCD has no decimal format.", "optd": "Binary coding is pure binary.", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to BCD.127", "opta": "011100100001", "optb": "111010001", "optc": "001010111", "optd": "000100100111", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Digital electronics is based on the ________ numbering system.", "opta": "decimal", "optb": "octal", "optc": "binary", "optd": "hexadecimal", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "An informational signal that makes use of binary digits is considered to be:", "opta": "solid state", "optb": "digital", "optc": "analog", "optd": "non-oscillating", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 1's complement of 10011101 is ________.", "opta": "01100010", "optb": "10011110", "optc": "01100001", "optd": "01100011", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary number 101110101111010 can be written in octal as ________.", "opta": "515628", "optb": "565778", "optc": "656278", "optd": "565728", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 45710 to hexadecimal.", "opta": "711", "optb": "2C7", "optc": "811", "optd": "1C9", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the decimal number 151.75 to binary.", "opta": "10000111.11", "optb": "11010011.01", "optc": "00111100.00", "optd": "10010111.11", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following octal number to binary.1048", "opta": "0010001002", "optb": "1000000012", "optc": "00101002", "optd": "10000012", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "3 \u00d7 101 + 7 \u00d7 100 is equal to ________.", "opta": "3.7", "optb": "37", "optc": "10", "optd": "370", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "3428 is the decimal value for which of the following binary-coded decimal (BCD) groupings?", "opta": "11010001001000", "optb": "11010000101000", "optc": "011010010000010", "optd": "110100001101010", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary-coded decimal (BCD) system can be used to represent each of the 10 decimal digits as a(n):", "opta": "4-bit binary code", "optb": "8-bit binary code", "optc": "16-bit binary code", "optd": "ASCII code", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The decimal number 18 is equal to the binary number ________.", "opta": "11110", "optb": "10001", "optc": "10010", "optd": "1111000", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The 2's complement of 11100111 is ________.", "opta": "11100110", "optb": "00011001", "optc": "00011000", "optd": "00011010", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to BCD.469", "opta": "100101101000", "optb": "010001101001", "optc": "100001101001", "optd": "100101100100", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Express the decimal number \u201337 as an 8-bit number in sign-magnitude.", "opta": "10100101", "optb": "00100101", "optc": "11011000", "optd": "11010001", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following BCD number to decimal.010101101001bcd", "opta": "539", "optb": "2551", "optc": "569", "optd": "1552", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary number 11001110 is equal to the decimal number ________.", "opta": "12", "optb": "206", "optc": "127", "optd": "66", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The binary number for F3A16 is ________.", "opta": "111100111010", "optb": "111100111110", "optc": "000000111010", "optd": "000011000100", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following BCD number to decimal.100000000011bcd", "opta": "8003", "optb": "803", "optc": "1003", "optd": "103", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following hexadecimal number to binary. 14B16", "opta": "1011010000012", "optb": "0001010010112", "optc": "0001010011012", "optd": "1101010000012", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the result when a decimal 5238 is converted to base 16?", "opta": "327.375", "optb": "12.166", "optc": "1388", "optd": "1476", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The octal number for binary 1101110101110110 is ________.", "opta": "6545218", "optb": "5565618", "optc": "1566568", "optd": "1565668", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following hexadecimal number to decimal.1CF16", "opta": "463", "optb": "4033", "optc": "479", "optd": "4049", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the binary number 1011010 to hexadecimal.", "opta": "5B", "optb": "5F", "optc": "5A", "optd": "5C", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to hexadecimal.74", "opta": "A416", "optb": "B416", "optc": "4A16", "optd": "4B16", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert hexadecimal C0B to binary.", "opta": "110000001011", "optb": "110000001001", "optc": "110000001100", "optd": "110100001011", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert binary 1001 to hexadecimal.", "opta": "916", "optb": "1116", "optc": "10116", "optd": "1016", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 73116 to decimal.", "opta": "216.4", "optb": "985", "optc": "3D9", "optd": "1841", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "What is the decimal value of the hexadecimal number 777?", "opta": "191", "optb": "1911", "optc": "19", "optd": "19111", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 110010012 (binary) to decimal.", "opta": "201", "optb": "2001", "optc": "20", "optd": "210", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following decimal number to octal.39", "opta": "638", "optb": "368", "optc": "478", "optd": "748", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The American Standard Code for Information Interchange (ASCII) uses how many individual pulses for any given character?", "opta": "1", "optb": "2", "optc": "7", "optd": "8", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert the following hexadecimal number to decimal.B516", "opta": "212", "optb": "197", "optc": "165", "optd": "181", "ans": "D", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The BCD number for decimal 16 is ________.", "opta": "00010110", "optb": "00010000", "optc": "00010010", "optd": "11100000", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Alphanumeric codes should include as a minimum:", "opta": "the capacity to represent the alphabet upper- and lowercase characters and the decimal numbers in a straight binary format.", "optb": "the capacity to code all possible decimal numbers in a direct octal representation of BCD codes.", "optc": "the alphabet upper- and lowercase letters, the decimal digits, the seven punctuation marks, and other characters or symbols.", "optd": "the ability to represent decimal numbers greater than 12810 in a straight binary format.", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 52716 to binary.", "opta": "343", "optb": "001101000111", "optc": "010100100111", "optd": "011100100101", "ans": "C", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Convert 5278 to binary.", "opta": "011100111", "optb": "101010111", "optc": "343", "optd": "111010101", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "The base of the hexadecimal system is:", "opta": "eight.", "optb": "sixteen.", "optc": "ten.", "optd": "two.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Assign the proper even parity bit to the code 1100001.", "opta": "11100001", "optb": "1100001", "optc": "01100001", "optd": "01110101", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Select one of the following statements that best describes the parity method of error detection.", "opta": "Parity checking is best suited for detecting single-bit errors in transmitted codes.", "optb": "Parity checking is not suitable for detecting single-bit errors in transmitted codes.", "optc": "Parity checking is capable of detecting and correcting errors in transmitted codes.", "optd": "Parity checking is best suited for detecting double-bit errors that occur during the transmission of codes from one location to another.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "Which of the following is the primary advantage of using the BCD code instead of straight binary coding?", "opta": "Fewer bits are required to represent a decimal number with the BCD code.", "optb": "The relative ease of converting to and from decimal.", "optc": "BCD codes are easily converted to hexadecimal codes.", "optd": "BCD codes are easily converted to straight binary codes.", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "How many BCD code bits and how many straight binary bits would be required to represent the decimal number 643?", "opta": "12 BCD, 12 binary", "optb": "12 BCD, 10 binary", "optc": "12 BCD, 9 binary", "optd": "16 BCD, 9 binary", "ans": "B", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}, {"question": "When using the repeated division by 2 method of converting from decimal to binary, one must write the first remainder as the:", "opta": "MSB", "optb": "MSB, provided the following sequence of remainders are written in descending order until the final remainder is achieved.", "optc": "LSB", "optd": "LSB, provided the final remainder is used to replace the original LSB, which is then moved to the MSB position.", "ans": "A", "explanation": "No answer description available for this question. Let us discuss."}]]}